翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So far, our SLList class has these two methods,
到目前为止，我们的 SLList 类有两个方法
and we made a sequence of these four non-obvious improvements.
并做了四个不明显的改进
And we want our SLList to gain even more power, and more capabilities,
我们希望 SLList 获得更多的功能
and go off and grow up and do whatever it is that SLList do in adulthood.
然后离开成长为一个真正的 SLList
And to get there, what we're going to do is add two additional methods--
为了这一点，我们要增加两个额外的方法
addLast and size--
addLast 和 size
partially because we want to get a little more practice just building data structures,
既为了获得更多构建数据结构的练习
but also because I want some motivation for the other two non-obvious improvements we're going to do.
又因为我想激励我们去做另外两个不明显的改进
So what I'm going to recommend you do
所以我建议
is try writing addLast or size on your own, maybe on paper,
试着自己写 addLast 或 size，也许是写在纸上
and then watch me do it here.
然后再看我写
So I'm going to start with addLast.
我将从 addLast 开始
So I'm going to call this method--
把这个方法称为...
it's going to be, oops--
这将会是...
public void addLast int x.
public void addLast(int x)
And in keeping with normal Java convention,
为了与常规的 Java 约定保持一致
I will put it above main.
我会把它放在 main 上方
And this adds an item to the end of the list.
它向 List 的尾部添加一个元素
So what might this look like?
应该是什么样呢？
Well, I'm going to write it iteratively.
我将使用迭代的方式编写
You can also do it recursively.
你也可以使用递归
I'm going to do it iteratively.
我会使用迭代
And it's going to look a lot like what we did in the previous lecture.
它跟我们上节课做的很像
So I'm going to say, int list p equals first.
IntList p = first
And then I'm going to say, while p.next is not equal to null,
然后是 while (p.next != null)
p equals p.next.
p = p.next
And the goal of this little chunk of code-- oops--
这一小段代码的目标是...
the goal of this little chunk of code is to scan p to the end of the list.
是将 p 扫描到 List 的尾部
So move p until it reaches the end of the list.
移动 p 直到 List 的尾部
And once you've done that, you can simply--
完成后，你就可以简单地...
jeez-- you can just simply say, p.next equals new int node x null. OK?
很简单 p.next = new IntNode(x, null)
So that's addLast.
这就是 addLast
We can also do l.addLast, let's say 20.
我们也可以调用 L.addLast()，比方说20
And if we run this, let's see what happens. OK.
运行这个，让我们看看会发生什么
Any errors?
有什么错误吗？
Oh, int node. Oops. Int node.
啊 IntNode
So we run this, and it runs, and the first item is 5.
运行它，显示第一项是5
Now, of course, running this code,
现在运行这段代码
it is not clear that it worked properly.
还不清楚它是否工作正常
And in fact, if you look at our list of methods,
事实上，如果你看看我们的方法列表
there's no way that we can see what the last item even is.
根本没法看到最后一项
So we could add additional methods,
所以我们可以添加额外的方法
but instead, what I'm going to do
但是相反，我要做的是
is I am going to use our Java visualizer and see what we get.
使用 Java visualizer 看看我们会得到什么
So after this code finishes running,
运行完这段代码后
we end up getting a layout that looks something like this.
我们最终得到了一个类似于下面的布局
The l variable points that our middle man,
变量 L 指向中间人
which has a first variable that then points at our naked recursive data structure.
它有第一个变量，然后指向我们的裸递归数据结构
And I'll make one little note--
做一个小笔记
if you try running this code on your own and you end up getting a visualization that looks something like this--
如果你试着自己运行这段代码，最后得到的可视化效果是这样的
like a nested structure--
像一个嵌套的结构
it's just another visual representation of the same thing.
这只是另一种视觉表现
If you don't want that to happen,
如果你不想让这种情况发生
make sure that you click Preferred, Non-nesting, and Vertical layouts.
确保选择“首选非嵌套和垂直布局”
So just a quick note, if you want box and pointer diagrams,
简单说明一下，如果你需要框图和指针图
you've got to click that box for our lists.
你必须点击那个框才能看到我们的 List
So that's getBack.
这就是 getBack
So what about size?
那么 size 呢？
What might size look like?
size 应该是什么样的？
Now, this one, if you didn't do addLast--
如果你没有尝试 addList
if you just sat there and watched me do it, that's OK. I won't be too upset.
你只是坐在那里看我做，没关系我不会很难过
But this one, I want you to really try.
但这次，我希望你真的试一试
I want you to really think about it.
我想让你好好思考一下
Look at the instance variables here, and think, what should size look like?
看看这里的实例变量，想一想 size 应该是什么样子
Try writing it out.
试着把它写出来
That's my way of trying to stare you into trying it.
这就是我想吓唬你试一试的方式
All right.
好的
So if you tried it, which hopefully you did,
所以如果你试过了，希望你已经试过了
you'll find that trying to figure out what the base case is is tricky.
你会发现，很难找出 base case
You also find that the recursive case is just equally strange.
你还会发现递归情况也同样奇怪
It's like if I want to do the recursive case like we did in the previous lecture,
就像我们上节课的做的递归
it would seem that you want to do something like return first.next size--
你应该做类似的东西，比如 return first.next.size
who knows, like, some kind of recursive case,
类似这样的递归条件
and you get a little stuck.
然后你就会有点卡住了
So the issue here is that the size method--
所以这里的问题是 size 方法...
when we're writing it for SLList, the SLList data structure itself is not recursive.
当我们为 SLList 编写它时，SLList 数据结构本身不是递归的
It does not have SLList pointers.
它没有 SLList 指针
So the common strategy that we'll adopt--
所以我们要采取的共同策略是...
and you'll see this time and time again as you write recursive data structures later in this course--
在本课程后面编写递归数据结构时，你将一次又一次地看到这一点
you'll often create a private static helper method--
你通常会创建一个 private static 的帮助方法
in this case, also known as size--
也称为 size
that is going to take a particular node--
它需要一个特定的节点
and this, I'm going to give a very clear comment here--
我将在这给出一个非常明确的注释
returns the size of the list that starts at int node p.
返回从 intNode p 开始的列表的大小
So here, now, this is a naked recursive data structure.
所以现在这是一个裸露的递归数据结构
This speaks the secret language of the gods, this data structure.
这个数据结构讲神的秘密语言
It's just doing the usual stuff we're used to with these data structures.
它只是在做我们习惯于处理这些数据结构的事情
Let me go back to the picture and compare.
让我回到幻灯片上来比较一下
So when we're working with SLLists,
当我们使用 SLList 时
our pointers point to the middle man.
我们的指针指向中间人
We are now going down a method that's thinking about data structures in these terms--
我们现在使用这些术语来考虑数据结构
in the naked recursive way, where we can pointers to any place in the list, OK?
在裸递归实现方式中，我们可以指向 List 的任意位置
So how is that going to work?
那么这会怎样工作呢？
Well, now it's going to be a lot like lecture 3.
现在很像第3课的情况
I'm going to do something like this.
这样做
If p.next equals null, then I can just return 1.
if (p.next == null)，则返回 1
Otherwise, we want to return 1 plus the size of p.next.
否则返回 1 + size(p.next)
So if the size method is being called on this node,
如果在此节点上调用 size 方法
for example, it'll just return 1.
例如它只返回1
But if it's called on this one, it'll add 1 plus the size of this list over here. OK?
但是如果在这个节点上调用，则为1加上这个 List 的大小
So that's what our private static method looks like.
这就是我们的 private static 方法
Now, this is a very common pattern when working with recursive data structures,
在处理递归数据结构时，这是一种非常常见的模式
that you'll have a public method that speaks the language of mortals and a private method that speaks the language of the gods.
你会有一个说凡人语言的 public 方法和一个说神语言的 private 方法
So the public language-- or sorry, the middleman-- the public method needs to use this method right here.
public 方法需要使用这个中间人
And in this case, we'll just say the size of first.
这种情况下返回 size(first)
That little face I just made was me trying to get you to think.
我刚才做的那个小鬼脸就是想让你思考
I don't know if it worked.
不知道有没有用...
And so let's see if the size method seems to work here. OK.
让我们看看 size 方法是否正常工作
Indeed, it does.
确实如此
And if you want to try it out, you can take this code that I've just written,
如果你想试一下，可以用我刚刚写的这段代码
put it through the visualizer, and make sure it makes sense.
把它放进可视化工具，确保它有意义
But hopefully, the idea is clear.
这个思路是明确的
So to summarize this notion--
总结一下这个概念
so, I'm sorry.
抱歉
To summarize addLast iteratively, not a lot of surprises.
反复总结 addLast 没有太多惊喜
You know, it's kind of like we're used to.
我们已经习惯这些了
But for size, doing it recursively,
但是对 size 而言，递归地实现它
we had to adopt new programming pattern
我们不得不采用新的编程模式
where we created a private static method that spoke the language of the gods.
创建了一个能说神之语的 private static 方法
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）